Collis Potter Huntington Papers
Collis Potter Huntington Papers
- Letterpress copybooks
  - Southern Pacific Company
    - Volume 181, Sept. 29, 1887 - Jan. 10, 1888 (Box 180)
    - Volume 182, Jan. 9, 1888 - June 20, 1888 (Box 180)
    - Volume 183, June 20, 1888 - Dec. 20, 1888 (Box 180)
    - Volume 184, Dec. 21, 1888 - July 11, 1889 (Box 180)
    - Volume 185, July 11, 1889 - Jan. 30, 1890 (Box 181)
    - Volume 186, Feb. 3, 1890 - July 2, 1890 (Box 181)
    - Volume 187, July 2, 1890 - Nov. 28, 1890 (Box 181)
    - Volume 188, Nov. 28, 1890 - Jan. 29, 1891 (Box 181)
    - Volume 189, Dec. 11, 1891 - Dec. 30, 1891 (Box 182)
  - Babbidge, Charles, and T. B. Curtis
    - Volume 190, May 1, 1895 - Nov. 18, 1899 (Box 182)
    - Volume 191, Nov. 24, 1899 - Nov. 1, 1900 (Box 182)
  - Butterfield, David
    - Volume 192, July 12, 1882 - Oct. 25, 1883 (Box 182)
  - Colburn, Richard T.
    - Volume 193, Oct. 30, 1875 - Nov. 13, 1877 (Box 183)
    - Volume 194, Nov. 6, 1877 - July 1, 1879 (Box 183)
    - Volume 195, July 2, 1879 - Dec. 17, 1880 (Box 183)
    - Volume 196, Dec. 10, 1880 - June 29, 1882 (Box 184)
    - Volume 197, July 1, 1882 - March 6, 1883 (Box 184)
    - Volume 198, Feb. 27, 1883 - Oct. 17, 1883 (Box 185)
    - Volume 199, Oct. 16, 1883 - Nov. 11, 1884 (Box 185)
    - Volume 200, Nov. 14, 1884 - May 22, 1886 (Box 185)
    - Volume 201, May 24, 1886 - May 28, 1887 (Box 186)
    - Volume 202, May 31, 1887 - Aug. 17, 1888 (Box 186)
  - Davis, Frank H.
    - Volume 203, Feb. 1, 1892 - Nov. 24, 1894 (Box 186)
  - Fillmore, J. A. to Alban N. Towne
    - Volume 204, Dec. 7, 1889 - Feb. 21, 1890 (Box 186)
  - Gates, Isaac Edwin
    - Volume 205, Jan. 2, 1892 - Sept. 15, 1892 (Box 186)
    - Volume 206, Sept. 15, 1892 - July 31, 1893 (Box 187)
    - Volume 207, July 31, 1893 - July 16, 1894 (Box 187)
  - Gates, Isaac Edwin (Personal)
    - Volume 208, Jan. 17, 1887 - Feb. 20, 1888 (Box 187)
    - Volume 209, Feb. 23, 1888 - Nov. 10, 1888 (Box 187)
    - Volume 210, March 27, 1889 - July 5, 1889 (Box 188)
    - Volume 211, July 5, 1889 - March 18, 1890 (Box 188)
    - Volume 212, March 19, 1890 - April 16, 1891 (Box 188)
    - Volume 213, April 20, 1891 - June 21, 1894 (Box 188)
  - Gates, Isaac Edwin (Private)
    - Volume 214, Oct. 17, 1892 - June 30, 1893 (Box 189)
    - Volume 215, June 30, 1893 - May 1, 1894 (Box 189)
    - Volume 216, April 10, 1895 - May 2, 1896 (Box 189)
    - Volume 217, May 5, 1896 - July 23, 1897 (Box 189)
    - Volume 218, July 26, 1897 - Jan. 14, 1899 (Box 190)
    - Volume 219, Jan. 16, 1899 - Jan. 11, 1900 (Box 190)
    - Volume 220, Jan. 13, 1900 - Jan. 5, 1901 (Box 190)
  - Huntington, Collis P. (Miscellaneous-Personal)
    - Volume 221, July 14, 1874 - May 20, 1875 (Box 191)
  - Huntington, Collis P. (Private-Personal)
    - Volume 222, Jan. 5, 1889 - Dec. 6, 1889 (Box 191)
  - Huntington, Collis P. (Miscellaneous-Private)
    - Volume 223, Jan. 2, 1892 - Jan. 10, 1892 (Box 191)
    - Volume 224, Jan. 11, 1892 - Feb. 15, 1892 (Box 191)
    - Volume 225, Feb. 16, 1892 - March 12, 1892 (Box 191)
    - Volume 226, March 14, 1892 - May 9, 1892 (Box 191)
    - Volume 227, May 10, 1892 - June 13, 1892 (Box 191)
    - Volume 228, June 14, 1892 - July 29, 1892 (Box 192)
    - Volume 229, Aug. 1, 1892 - Sept. 14, 1892 (Box 192)
    - Volume 230, Sept. 17, 1892 - Oct. 7, 1892 (Box 192)
    - Volume 231, Oct. 10, 1892 - Nov. 15, 1892 (Box 192)
    - Volume 232, Nov. 16, 1892 - Dec. 31, 1892 (Box 192)
    - Volume 233, Jan. 1, 1893 - Jan. 31, 1893 (Box 193)
    - Volume 234, Feb. 1, 1893 - March 11, 1893 (Box 193)
    - Volume 235, March 12, 1893 - April 10, 1893 (Box 193)
    - Volume 236, April 11, 1893 - May 15, 1893 (Box 193)
    - Volume 237, May 16, 1893 - June 20, 1893 (Box 194)
    - Volume 238, June 21, 1893 - June 30, 1893 (Box 194)
    - Volume 239, July 1, 1893 - Aug. 17, 1893 (Box 194)
    - Volume 240, Aug. 18, 1893 - Sept. 27, 1893 (Box 194)
    - Volume 241, Sept. 28, 1893 - Nov. 10, 1893 (Box 195)
    - Volume 242, Nov. 16, 1893 - Dec. 30, 1893 (Box 195)
    - Volume 243, Jan. 2, 1894 - Feb. 3, 1894 (Box 195)
    - Volume 244, Feb. 12, 1894 - March 31, 1894 (Box 195)
    - Volume 245, April 4, 1894 - May 7, 1894 (Box 195)
    - Volume 246, May 17, 1894 - July 19, 1894 (Box 196)
    - Volume 247, July 24, 1894 - Jan. 25, 1895 (Box 196)
    - Volume 248, Jan. 30, 1895 - Feb. 2, 1895 (Box 196)
    - Volume 249, March 11, 1895 - April 20, 1895 (Box 196)
    - Volume 250, May 20, 1895 - Sept. 29, 1896 (Box 196)
    - Volume 251, Oct. 1, 1896 - Nov. 15, 1897 (Box 196)
    - Volume 252, Nov. 18, 1897 - Sept. 15, 1898 (Box 197)
    - Volume 253, Sept. 16, 1898 - March 29, 1899 (Box 197)
    - Volume 254, April 5, 1899 - Dec. 15, 1899 (Box 197)
    - Volume 255, Dec. 13, 1899 - Feb. 17, 1900 (Box 197)
  - Collis P. to W. V. Huntington and Huntington, Charles F. Crocker
    - Volume 256, Oct. 1, 1878 - Oct. 12, 1883 (Box 198)
  - Telegrams
    - Volume 257, Oct. 19, 1871 - Jan. 29, 1879 (Box 198)
    - Volume 258, Jan. 30, 1879 - June 24, 1882 (Box 198)
    - Volume 259, June 28, 1882 - March 22, 1888 (Box 198)
    - Miscellaneous books (Box 219)
- Legal and financial records
  - Corporate
    - Ashland Improvement Co., 1886 (Box 220)
    - Central American Pacific Railway & Transportation Co., 1882 (Box 220)
    - Central Pacific Railroad, 1870-1872; 1874-1879,; 1881-1882,; undated (Box 220)
    - Chesapeake & Nashville Railroad, 1889 (Box 220)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Railway Co., 1869-1870; 1878-1880,; 1882-1889,; undated (Box 220)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Elevator Co., 1881; 1886 (Box 220)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Railway Coal Agency, 1877-1885 (Box 220)
    - Chesapeake, Ohio & South Western Railroad, 1885 (Box 220)
    - Congo Railroad Co., 1892 (Box 220)
    - Elizabethtown, Lexington & Big Sandy Railroad, 1872-1874; 1880,; 1887 (Box 220)
    - Ensign Manufacturing Co., 1883; 1884,; 1887 (Box 220)
    - Fisk & Hatch, ca. 1873 (Box 220)
    - Forest Park Land Co., 1898-1899 (Box 220)
    - Galveston, Harrisburg & San Antonio Railway Co., 1882 (Box 220)
    - Hammond Lumber Co., undated (Box 220)
    - Huntington Hopkins Co., 1871; 1874,; 1879-1990,; 1883-1885,; 1887,; 1894 (Box 220)
    - Huntington Steamship Co., Oct. 1887 - June 18, 1888 (Box 220)
    - Kentucky Central Railway Co., 1890 (Box 220)
    - Louisville & Nashville Railroad Co., 1889 (Box 220)
    - Louisville, Cincinnati & Lexington Railroad, 1874-1876 (Box 220)
    - Louisville, Evansville & St. Louis Railway Co., 1885 (Box 220)
    - Market Street Omnibus Co., 1891-1892 (Box 220)
    - Newport News & Mississippi Valley Co., 1889-1893 (Box 220)
    - Occidental & Oriental Steamship Co., 1875-1880 (Box 220)
    - Old Dominion Steamship Co., 1879; 1893-1898 (Box 220)
    - Owensboro, Falls of Rough Green River Railroad Co., 1892 (Box 220)
    - Pacific Improvement Co., 1892 (Box 220)
    - Raquette Lake Railway Co., 1899-1900; undated (Box 220)
    - Richmond Elevator Co., 1883 (Box 220)
    - Southern Development Corp., 1887 (Box 220)
    - Southern Pacific Railroad, 1879-1880; 1899,; undated (Box 220)
    - Texas & New Orleans Railway, 1883 (Box 220)
    - Western Development Co., 1877-1879; 1882,; 1887,; undated (Box 220)
    - Unidentified, 1871-1891 (Box 220)
  - Personal
    - Account Books
      - Cash Book
        - Volume 230, April 1, 1875 - Jan. 1, 1877 (Box 221)
        - Volume 231, May 1, 1876 - Dec. 31, 1877 (Box 221)
        - Volume 232, Jan. 1, 1878 - Oct. 15, 1878 (Box 221)
        - Volume 233, Jan., 1886 - April, 1887 (Oversize 1)
        - Volume 234, May, 1887 - May, 1888 (Oversize 2)
        - Volume 235, June, 1888 - March, 1889 (Oversize 3)
        - Volume 236, April, 1889 - Jan. 1, 1890 (Oversize 4)
      - Day Books
        - Volume 237, Oct. 9, 1871 - Aug. 22, 1874, incl. journal (Box 221)
        - Volume 238, April 5, 1875 - Dec. 30, 1876, incl. journal and cash book (Box 221)
      - Journals
        - Volume 239, Jan., 1886 - Nov. 1888 (Oversize 5)
        - Volume 240, Dec., 1888 - Dec., 1889 (Oversize 6)
        - Volume 241, Jan., 1890 - Sept. 1891 (Oversize 7)
        - Volume 242, Oct. 1891 - Dec., 1892 (Oversize 8)
        - Volume 243, Jan., 1893 - Dec., 1893 (Oversize 9)
        - Volume 244, Jan., 1894 - Dec., 1894 (Oversize 10)
        - Volume 245, Jan., 1895 - June, 1896 (Oversize 11)
        - Volume 246, July, 1896 - Aug., 1898 (Oversize 12)
      - Ledgers
        - Volume 247, Jan., 1890 - Dec., 1891 (Oversize 13)
        - Volume 248, Jan., 1892 - Dec., 1893 (Oversize 14)
    - Civil Suits
      - Henry Y. Attree v. Rockaway Beach Improvement Co., Ltd., et al., 1881 (Box 222)
      - William Cheney v. Solon Huntington, et al., 1879 (Box 222)
      - Ellen M. Colton v. Leland Stanford, et al.
        - Printed court record, 4 volumes, 1883-1885 (Box 222)
        - Court records
          - Volume I, Nov. 13, 1883 (Box 222)
          - Volume II (fifth day), Nov. 20, 1883 (Box 222)
          - Volume III (ninth day), Dec. 4, 1883 (Box 222)
          - Volume IV (thirteenth day), Dec. 11, 1883 (Box 222)
          - Volume V (seventeenth day), Dec. 18, 1883 (Box 222)
          - Volume VI (nineteenth day), Jan. 9, 1884 (Box 223)
          - Volume VII (twenty-second day), Feb. 12, 1884 (Box 223)
          - Volume VIII (twenty-sixth day), Feb. 19, 1884 (Box 223)
          - Volume IX (twenty-ninth day), April 1, 1884 (Box 223)
          - Volume X (thirty-third day), April 8, 1884 (Box 223)
          - Volume XI (thirty-sixth day), April 23, 1884 (Box 223)
          - Volume XII (thirty-ninth day), April 29, 1884 (Box 224)
          - Volume XIII (forty-third day), May 6, 1884 (Box 224)
          - Volume XIV (forty-sixth day), May 13, 1884 (Box 224)
          - Volume XV (forty-ninth day), May 20, 1884 (Box 224)
          - Volume XVI (fifty-third day), May 27, 1884 (Box 224)
          - Volume XVII (fifty-sixth day), June 3, 1884 (Box 224)
          - Volume XVIII (sixtieth day), June 10, 1884 (Box 225)
          - Volume XIX (sixty-fourth day), June 17, 1884 (Box 225)
          - Volume XX (sixty-eighth day), June 24, 1884 (Box 225)
          - Volume XXI (seventy-second day), July 1, 1884 (Box 225)
          - Volume XXII (seventy-fourth day), July 8, 1884 (Box 225)
          - Volume XXIII (seventy-eighth day), July 22, 1884 (Box 226)
          - Volume XXIV (eighty-first day), July 30, 1884 (Box 226)
        - Depositions, 5 volumes (Box 226)
        - Defense arguments, 5 volumes (Box 227)
        - Digest of testimony (Box 227)
        - Plaintiff arguments, 2 volumes (Box 227)
        - Index of evidence (Box 227)
        - Index of testimony, 3 volumes (Box 227)
        - Colton v. Stanford, notes of counsel for the defense, 1883-1885; 4 folders (Box 228)
        - Supporting material for the defense
          - Account Books of David D. Colton
            - Cash book (Volume 295), Sept. 1, 1874 - April 1, 1875 (Box 228)
            - Journals (Volumes 296 and 297, January 1, 1877-October 9, 1878 (Oversize 15)
            - Ledger (Volumes 298, 299), April, 1875 - Oct. 1878; 2 volumes (Box 228)
          - Statements of Account
            - D. D. Colton with London & San Francisco Bank Ltd. (Volume 300), Jan. 1, 1870 - Nov. 25, 1878 (Oversize 15)
            - D. D. Colton with First National Gold Bank (Volume 301), Jan. 1, 1871 - Oct. 22, 1877 (Box 228)
            - D. D. Colton with ???, April 20, 1876 - Oct. 9, 1878 (Box 228)
            - D. D. Colton with Western Development Co. (Volume 302), July 13, 1876 - Oct. 17, 1878 (Box 228)
            - Central Pacific Railway Co. with D. D.Colton (Volume 303), June 20, 1876 - Dec. 4, 1878 (Box 228)
            - Pacific Improvement Co. with Western Development Co. (Volume 304), Nov. 6, 1878 - June 30, 1879 (Box 228)
            - Western Development Co. with D. D. Colton (Volume 305), Nov. 8, 1876 - July 30, 1879 (Box 228)
          - Deposit slips for D. D. Colton
            - London and San Francisco Bank, Ltd., Jan. 1, 1874 - Dec. 31, 1875 (Box 228)
            - London and San Francisco Bank, Ltd., Apr. 1, 1875 - Sept. 17, 1878 (Box 229)
          - Check books of D.D. Colton
            - Volume 306, Dec. 30, 1873 - Aug. 25, 1875 (Oversize 16-1)
            - Volume 307, Aug. 25, 1875 - Aug. 27, 1877 (Oversize 16-2)
            - Volume 308, Nov. 15, 1875 - April 15, 1877 (Oversize 16-3)
            - Volume 309, Aug. 25, 1877 - March 12, 1878 (Oversize 16-4)
          - List of checks drawn in favor of D. D. Colton (Volume 310), June 12, 1875 - Oct. 1, 1878 (Box 229)
          - Notes and bills payable of D. D. Colton (Volume 311), Oct. 16, 1876 - Sept. 2, 1878 (Box 229)
          - Assets and liabilities of Western Development Co. (Volume 312), Aug. 27, 1879 (Box 229)
          - Memoranda of agreement between D. D. Colton and others (Volume 313), Jan. 23, 1877 (Box 229)
      - Leopold Goldsmith v. Solon Huntington et al., 1879 (Box 229)
      - Chew Heong v. United States, dissenting opinion of Justice Field, 1884 (Box 229)
      - Edward J. Muybridge v. Leland Stanford
        - Correspondence, 1883 (Box 229)
        - Notices, plaintiff's declaration, defendant's answer, 1883 (Box 229)
        - Depositions, 1883; 5 folders (Box 229)
        - Miscellaneous, 1883 (Box 229)
      - Charles B. Polheums v. Charles Mayne, 1892; subpoena (Box 229)
      - David Stewart v. Collis P. Huntington, et al., May, 1883; proceedings at trial on circuit (Box 230)
      - United States v. M. Crooks, et al., 1884; transcript on appeal (Box 230)
    - Investment ledgers
      - Stocks (Volume 316), February 1876-March 1878 (Box 231)
      - Investments (Volume 317), October 1876-October 1878 (Box 231)
      - Register of securities (Volume 318), January 2, 1890-December 10, 1902 (Box 231)
      - Securities (Volume 319), April 1892-Dec 1899 (Box 231)
    - Loans payable and receivable
      - Notes payable, 1872; 1892 (Box 231)
      - Double book I, Notes payable, notes receivable, December 21, 1892-June 1, 1897; June 30, 1881-June 10, 1890 (Box 231)
      - Double book II, Notes payable, notes receivable (Volume 320), December 1895-December 1899 (Box 232)
      - Double book III, Mortgages payable and receivable, May 1, 1867-June 19, 1890; March 9, 1868-June 13, 1890 (Box 232)
    - Personal Bills
      - 1863 (Box 232)
      - 1867-1869, 3 folders (Box 232)
      - 1870-1877, 9 folders (Box 233)
      - 1878-1881, 8 folders (Box 234)
      - 1882-1884 (Oct), 13 folders (Box 235)
      - 1884 (Nov)-1884 (Box 236)
      - 1885-1888, 1890-1895, undated (Box 236)
      - Oct 1892-Dec 1896 (Volume 324) (Oversize 17)
      - Jan 1897-Jul 1899 (Volume 325) (Oversize 18)
      - Aug 1899-Aug 1900 (Volume 326) (Oversize 19)
    - Real Estate
      - California
        - Butte County, 1892 (Box 236)
        - San Francisco, Colton House, 1892-1894; 1896; bills and receipts; 11 folders (Box 236)
        - San Francisco, 1899; property tax receipts for several lots (Box 236)
        - Santa Monica, 1892 (Box 236)
      - Connecticut
        - Bridgeport, 1875; 1880 (Box 237)
        - Cornwall, 1873-1875 (Box 237)
        - Harwinton, 1885-1888; 5 folders (Box 237)
        - Middletown, 1868-1869 (Box 237)
        - Wolcottville, 1856-1870 (Box 237)
      - Kentucky
        - Louisville, 1883-1895; 2 folders (Box 237)
        - Meade County, 1889 (Box 237)
      - Louisiana
        - Lafayette Parish, 1886 (Box 237)
      - Mississippi
        - Lincoln County - mill property, 1885 (Box 237)
      - New Brunswick, 1886 (Box 237)
      - New Jersey
        - Warwick, Pine Island Farm, 1797-1866; 1878-1881,; 1884-1890; 3 folders (Box 237)
      - New York
        - Brooklyn, Clifton Place, 1867-1876; 1881-1891; 3 folders (Box 238)
        - Brooklyn, 656 Nostrand Ave., 1875-1900; 2 folders (Box 238)
        - Brooklyn, Stockholm St., 1877-1889 (Box 238)
        - Brooklyn, Van Buren St., 1881 (Box 238)
        - Mount Pleasant, 1885 (Box 238)
        - New York City
          - City Island, Belden Point, 1888-1906; 1909,; 1912; 6 folders (Box 238)
          - 80th St. near Madison Ave., 1870-1894 (Box 239)
          - 5th Ave. & 80th St., 1868-1973; 1881-1891; 5 folders (Box 239)
          - 5th Ave. & 72nd St., 1885-1899 (Box 239)
          - 5 W. 51st St., 1882-1887 (Box 239)
          - 4 W. 54th St., 1884-1885 (Box 239)
          - W. 59th St., 1888-1894 (Box 239)
          - 2 W. 57th St., 1888-1893 (Jul); 8 folders (Box 239)
          - 2 W. 57th St., 1893 (Aug)-1896; 1899,; undated; last folder has photograph of bedroom suite; 8 folders (Box 240)
          - 65 Park Ave., 1867-1900 (Box 240)
          - Fourth Universalist Society PEW, 1868 (Box 240)
          - 109 Lexington Ave., 1874-1875; 1887 (Box 240)
          - Riverside Drive, 1880 (Box 240)
          - Saint Ann's St., 1869-1898; 3 folders (Box 241)
          - 124 E. 38th St., 1865-1890 (Box 241)
          - 126 E. 38th St., 1885-1896 (Box 241)
          - 118 W. 39th St., 1887; 1891-1892 (Box 241)
          - property and water taxes for properties, 1872-1894 (Box 241)
        - Oneonta, 1853-1878 (Oct); 6 folders (Box 241)
        - Oneonta, 1878 (Nov)-1890; undated; 6 folders (Box 242)
        - Raquette Lake, 1890; 1893,; 1895,; 1898-1901,; undated; 3 folders (Box 242)
        - Throgg's Neck, The Homestead, 1884-1889 (Box 242)
        - Westchester, Westchester Library and Reading Room, 1890-1896; 14 folders (Box 243)
        - Westchester, Woodlawn Cemetery, 1876 (Box 243)
      - Ohio
        - Cincinnati, 1883-1886; 2 folders (Box 244)
        - Columbus, 1887 (Box 244)
        - Mount Pleasant, 1886 (Box 244)
      - Tennessee
        - Memphis, 1881-1889 (Box 244)
      - Texas
        - Galveston, Virginia Point, 1883; 1891,; 1893 (Box 244)
        - Hays County, Belle Farm, 1886 (Box 244)
      - Virginia
        - Hampton, Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute, 1880-1885; 1888-1893; 5 folders (Box 244)
      - West Virginia
        - St. Albans, Abbott Hall, 1874-1880 (Box 244)
      - Record of Real Estate and Buildings
        - Volume 327, 1890-1896 (Oversize 20)
        - Volume 328, 1897-1900 (Oversize 21)
      - Statements of account, 1869-1870; 1873,; 1876,; 1878-1879,; 1882-1898; 4 folders (Box 244)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Financial statements, Oct 1893-Aug 1900 (Box 245)
      - Last Will and Testament of Collis P. Huntington, 1897 (Box 245)
      - Miscellaneous, 1872; 1881,; 1889,; 1898 (Box 245)
- Personal papers
  - Biographical Material
    - Autobiographical letter written by Collis P. Huntington to James Speyer, tsc, 24pp, Dec. 6, 1899 (Box 246)
    - Autobiographical notes, edited with biographical notes by Charles Nordhoff, ts, rev, holo, undated (Box 246)
    - Genealogical material collected by the Rev. E. B. Huntington, Incl. corr., 1863-1873 (Box 246)
    - Personal memorandum book, 1862-1868 (Box 246)
  - Material Relating to Collis P. Huntington's Business and Philanthropic Interests
    - African Interests, 1889-1890 (Box 246)
  - Organizational records
    - Austin and Northwestern Railway, ca. 1883 (Box 246)
    - Central Pacific Railroad, 1865; 1871-1872,; 1875-1880,; 1882,; 1885,; 1892,; undated (Box 246)
    - Chatteroi Railway, undated (Box 246)
    - Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Co., 1874; 1878-1880,; 1885-1886,; 1888-1889,; undated (Box 246)
    - Chesapeake Dry Dock and Construction Co., 1887 (Box 246)
    - Chesapeake, Ohio and Southwestern Railroad, 1883 (Box 246)
    - Cincinnati, Indianapolis, St. Louis & Chicago Railway Co., 1881 (Box 246)
    - Cincinnati, Portsmouth, Big Sandy and Pomeroy Packet Co., 1881 (Box 246)
    - Columbus, Hocking Valley and Toledo Railway, 1881 (Box 246)
    - Congo Railway Co., 1889-1893 (Box 246)
    - Connecticut Fire Insurance Co., 1879? (Box 246)
    - Contracting and Building Co., stockholders' minutes, Volume 328, 1871-1879 (Oversize 22)
    - Denver and Rio Grande Railroad Co., 1887 (Box 246)
    - Edison United Manufacturing Co., 1888 (Box 246)
    - Edmonson County Coal and Iron Co., 1889 (Box 246)
    - Elevated Railways of New York, 1884 (Box 246)
    - Elizabethtown, Lexington and Big Sandy Railroad, 1870; 1876,; 1878-1880 (Box 246)
    - Ensign Manufacturing Co., 1872; 1889,; 1891,; 1893-1894,; 1898 (Box 246)
    - Forest Park-Land Co., 1900 (Box 246)
    - Fort Scott, Wichita & Western Railway Co., 1887 (Box 246)
    - Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe Railroad Co., 1883 (Box 246)
    - Imperial British East India Co., 1889 (Box 246)
    - Kansas, Fort Scott and Memphis Railroad Co., 1888-1889 (Box 246)
    - Louisville, New Albany and St. Louis Railway Co., 1880 (Box 246)
    - Low Moor Iron Co., 1879; 1882-1887 (Box 246)
    - Marietta and North Georgia Railway Co., 1887 (Box 246)
    - Market Street Cable Railway Co., 1891-1892 (Box 246)
    - Metropolitan Opera House Co. of New York, Ltd., 1888; 1892 (Box 246)
    - Metropolitan Trust Co., 1884-1885; 1890 (Box 246)
    - Newport News and Mississippi Valley Co., 1887-1888 (Box 246)
    - Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Co., 1893; 1899,; undated (Box 246)
    - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Co., 1887 (Box 246)
    - New York Stock Exchange, 1887 (Box 246)
    - Occidental & Oriental Steamship Co., 1875; 1878 (Box 246)
    - Old Dominion Steamship Co., 1885; 1893 (Box 246)
    - Pacific Improvement Co., 1882; 1897 (Box 246)
    - Paducah and Memphis Railroad, minutes of Reorganization, trustee's Minute Book, 1876-1880 (Box 247)
    - Pennsylvania Co., 1887; 2 folders (Box 247)
    - Pintsch Lighting Co., 1887 (Box 247)
    - Raquette Lake Railway Co., 1900; undated (Box 247)
    - Richmond & Danville Railroad Co., 1887 (Box 247)
    - Richmond Elevator Co., 1885; 1887,; 1891
    - Sacramento Valley Railroad, 1875 (Box 247)
    - Scioto Valley Railway, 1884; locomotive specifications (Box 247)
    - Southern Pacific Railroad, 1875-1880; 1892 (Box 247)
    - Spring Mountain (Lehigh) Coal Co., 1872 (Box 247)
    - Suspension Car/Truck Manufacturing Co., 1881 (Box 247)
    - Texas & New Orleans Railway, 1881; 1885 (Box 247)
    - Western Union Telegraph Co., 1882; 1883,; 1885,; 1887,; 1888; quarterly reports (Box 247)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Materials regarding possible steel mill and gun manufacturing concern at Newport News, 1897-1898 (Box 247)
      - Proposal for a railroad from Columbus, Ohio, to Maysville, Kentucky, undated (Box 247)
      - Report on Los Angeles Cable Railway Co., ca. 1891 (Box 247)
      - Report regarding potentialities for a railroad in the Little Kanawha Valley, ca. 1892 (Box 247)
    - Stock Exchange Statements, Feb. 1887-Nov. 1889 (Box 247)
    - Unidentified, 1885 (Box 247)
- Miscellany
  - Memorabilia
    - Invitations, 1879; 1891 (Box 247)
    - Lists of guests at Collis P. Huntington's annual dinners in San Francisco, 1889; 1892 (Box 247)
    - Membership certificate of Collis P. Huntington in the Geographical Society of the Pacific, 1890 (Box 247)
    - News clippings
      - 1890, 1893-1894, 1896-1897, 1899 (Box 247)
      - The Tammany Times, 1894 (Box 247)
      - "Record of Fraud," The Examiner, Nov 1898 (Oversize 23A)
      - 1900, 4 folders (Box 247)
      - Aug 1900 (Oversize 23)
      - 1902, 1904, 1911 (Box 247)
      - 1924, 1928, 1929, 1934 (Box 247)
      - Undated (Box 247)
    - Portraits
      - Cartoons, (reprints and photo dup.), 1896-1897 (Box 247)
      - Engraving, ca. 1896 (Box 247)
      - Engravings, Collis P. Huntington, ca. 1899 (Oversize 24)
      - Mezzotint, Collis P. Huntington (Oversize 24)
      - Photo repro of painting of Collis P. Huntington by Francis Lathrop, undated (Box 247)
      - Photographs
        - Collis P. Huntington, middle age (Box 247)
        - Collis P. Huntington, late middle age, 6 prints (Box 248)
        - Collis P. Huntington, ca. 1896; 7 prints, 1 negative, 1 modern print (Box 248)